嘿  亲爱的
Hey, honey.
可能更糟糕的
It could be worse.
我不知道会怎样  但情况也许比现在更糟
I don't know how, but it could be.
我之前常去这家披萨店
So I used to go to this pizza parlor.
如果你在这过生日的话  他们可能会把派拍你脸上
There, when it was your birthday, they would give you a... a pie in the face.
他们有时候就是会做这么无聊的事
But they would do this cheap thing
他们有时候也会把剃须膏抹在纸盘子上
where they would put shaving cream on a paper plate
然后拍到你的脸上
and then smear it on your face.
- 很有意思  - 是的
- Nice. - Right.
之前有一次因为吃了薄荷  我得了皮疹
And, of course, I got a rash from the menthol.
而且那天和我约会的那个家伙  实在是倒胃口
And the guy that I was on the date with, it was really embarrassing.
好像叫劳伦斯还是什么的
His name was Lawrence or something.
他说我闻起来像个男人
He said I smelled like a man.
- 是吗  - 是啊
- Huh. - Right.
之后大家都在狂笑
And everybody laughed.
是有点糗
I'm sorry.
我怀孕了
I'm pregnant.
什么
What?
我说我怀孕了
I'm pregnant.
帮我拿着  我做了测验
Hold this. I have the test.
而且  我测了两次  好吧  到光下面来
l... I did it twice and... well, come in the light.
看见了吗  两次都是两条红线
See? Both times the pink line goes all the way across.
是的
Right.
所以说  我怀孕了
So... I'm pregnant.
你  你想要这个吗
ls this... is this what you want?
- 我想不想要一个孩子吗  - 是的
- Do I want to be pregnant? - Yeah.
不  我当然不想
No. No, I don't want to be.
那我们到底在谈什么呢
What are we talking about?
听着  这并不是我是想的样子  你明白吗
Well, look, it's not exactly the way l imagined it would happen, you know?
好吧  所以你想怎么做
Right. So what do you want to do?
我并不知道  尼克
I don't know, Nick.
那  你准备好做一个父亲了吗
Well, do you want to be a father?
法外真情
第三季  第八集
翻译   大淘  子
校对  油 球
特效  转轮 枪
有个无家可归的家伙  弗雷迪 · 墨菲
This homeless guy... Fred Murphy.
他一直在整个城市到处涂鸦信任两个字
He's been painting ''Believe'' all over the city.
信任
''Believe.''
医院  犯罪现场  房屋中介
Hospitals. Crime scenes. Housing projects.
他四处奔波想要努力传递一点希望
He goes and tries to spread a little hope around.
这种行为  说不清楚  很鼓舞人心吧
lt's, uh... I don't know... it's very... inspirational.
不管怎样  这是艾滋病救济联盟主席  维多利亚·里特尔小姐
Anyway... this is Victoria Little, Chairman of the AIDS Relief Alliance.
大家好
Hi, everybody.
由于艾滋病人徒步活动因雨取消
Uh... when the, uh, AIDS Walk was rained out,
艾滋病救济联盟损失了百分之三十的运营预算
the AIDS Relief Alliance lost thirty percent of their operating budget.
他们已经减少了很多计划  甚至包括法律服务的开支
They've already cut several of their programs, including their legal services.
是的  我和阿尔文最终决定
Right. And Alvin and I have decided
使用郡政府的补助  来为他们的客户辩护
to use some of our county funds to represent their clients.
顺便说一下  即将会有一个强制性的艾滋病意识培训研讨会
So, by the way, there will be a mandatory AIDS Awareness Training Seminar
从今天起  为期一周
a week from today.
我也会在这一周一直在这里答疑
And I'll be here all week to answer any questions.
而且  我们这周六正举行紧急筹款活动
Also, we're having an emergency fundraiser this Saturday.
会在焦油坑俱乐部举行一场假面舞会
lt's a masquerade party at The Tar Pit.
是一家几个月之前倒闭了的俱乐部
lt's this club that closed a few months ago.
也是为了减少一些徒步活动造成的损失
lt's to recover some of the losses from the walk.
并且  各位可以带一个客人来参加  免费的
And, uh... you and a guest are invited... free of charge.
所以  请带上你们的朋友们  尽量说服他们捐款
So please bring your friends, but make them pay.
信任
''Believe.''
你们大家应该看一看这篇文章
You guys, you gotta see this article.
信任  是吧
''Believe''... right?
有个家伙把这个涂得到处都是
The guy's painting it everywhere.
然后呢
So?
所以我觉得这是一次机会
So I think it's an opportunity.
什么  难道你想让我们去画这个家伙的标志吗
What, you want us to print this guy's symbol?
你们现在有一个很好的机会  摆脱困境
Well, you guys are in an ideal position to get it out there.
- 我们马上要破产了  - 快别再提这个了
- We're about to go belly-up. - Get it out there fast.
我的意思是  还有其他的商人屯了七万五千个马克杯  T恤
I mean, what other merchandiser's got seventy-five thousand mugs, T-shirts,
还有钥匙链在那积灰吗
and key chains sitting around collecting dust?
我们即使不用那个标志也可以
Yeah, well, we can move those units without a symbol on 'em
赚到二十万
for two hundred grand.
那是批发
That's wholesale.
但是如果印上信任这个想法成功了  可能就会价值数百万
But if this ''Believe'' idea works, it could be worth... millions.
那么  关于印刷的费用呢
Nah. What about printing costs?
那能多少钱啊  一件十美分
What's it gonna be, ten cents a unit?
每件十美分的话我们就得借钱了
Ten cents a unit we'd have to borrow.
帮我们摆脱债务才是当前要务
Thought the idea was to get out of debt.
信任
''Believe''?
t恤衫
T-shirts.
帽子
Hats.
钥匙链
Key chains.
请进
Come in.
- 在忙吗  - 没有  请坐
- You busy? - No. No. Have a seat.
- 你还好吗  - 挺好  你呢
- You okay? - Fine. You?
还不错
Yeah.
我  我在诊所预约了
l, uh... I made an appointment at a clinic.
诊所
Clinic?
是的  明天早上八点
Right. Tomorrow morning at 8.
诊所吗
Clinic?
是的  就是去  你也知道我现在的情况
Yeah. Just to, you know, see where I'm at.
去验下血  也再考虑一下
And get a blood test and weigh the options.
好吧
Right.
那  我明天陪你一起去吧
Well, uh... l... I'd like to be there.
早上八点
lt's at 8.
- 你告诉我了  - 嗯  是已经告诉你了
- You told me. - Oh, yeah.
- 嗨  尼克  -嘿
- Hi, Nick. - Hey.
这是马库斯 · 小麦和他的妹妹艾塔
This is Marcus Wheat and his sister Etta.
- 嘿  - 你好啊
- Hey. - What's up?
- 厉害  - 别急  你也能学会
- Okay. - Don't worry. You'll get it.
好吧  嘿
Okay. Hey.
你好
Hi.
- 你好吗  - 挺好的
- How are you? - Fine.
马库斯  能带你妹妹出去一下吗
Marcus, will you take your sister outside for just a second?
谢谢
Thank you.
你们可以去我刚刚告诉你们的地方玩玩具  好吗
You can play with the toys where I showed you, okay?
谢谢
Thank you.
拜拜
Bye.
我觉得我们需要去找一下达姆森法官
I think we need to go to Judge Damsen's chambers.
- 为什么  - 他们需要一个医疗监护人
- Why? - They need a medical guardian.
医疗监护人  怎么会呢
Medical guardian? What for?
因为他们的妈妈三天之前死于艾滋病  并且她拒绝给孩子们检查
Their mother died of AIDS three days ago, and she refused to have them tested.
那阿尔文提到的有争议的捐款又是怎么回事
So what's this Alvin mentioned about a contested donation?
呃  是我的一个朋友  叫沃伦·康纳
Well, there's a friend of mine, Warren Connor...
他三个月之前死了
he died three months ago,
给联盟留下了一百万美金
and he left the Alliance a million dollars,
但是他的孩子们对此很不满
and his kids aren't too happy about it.
所以  那你们需要我来解决这件事吗
Oh, so do you need me to handle it?
事实上  阿尔文说他认识那个律师
Well, actually, Alvin said that he knows the lawyer
就是康纳的孩子们的代理律师  所以
that's representing the Connor kids, so...
好吧
Hmm.
那  有什么我能帮上忙的吗
Well, uh... is there anything I can do to help?
当然  有一个叫天梯的俱乐部
Yes. In fact, there's this club called Lift.
- 表面上是一个男性体育俱乐部  - 是个同性恋俱乐部吗
- It's ostensibly a sports club for men. - A gay club?
是一个底层的男性
A place where minority men on the down low
和一些生活压抑的白人去的风月场所
and closeted white guys go for anonymous sex.
那么  我能帮上什么呢
And how can I help?
我们希望能有机会给他们进行免费的艾滋病检测  教育和预防
We want access, to provide free AIDS testing, education, prevention.
我没办法接触到他们
I haven't been able to get anywhere with them,
所以我觉得  作为一个律师  也许你能引起他们的注意
so I thought, since you're a lawyer, you might be able to get their attention.
好吧
Okay.
准备好了吗
You ready?
就现在吗
lt's time?
是啊  会议二十分钟后开始  伯顿向来很准时
Yeah. Meeting's in twenty minutes. Burton's very punctual.
他们的妈妈从没给他们做过检查吗
Their mother never tested them?
是的
Correct.
那他们的爸爸呢
What about the father?
还在找
We're still looking.
佩尔小姐  要知道你并没有义务
Miss Pell, you understand you're under no obligation
去给孩子们做检查
to have these children tested.
我知道
Yes.
好吧
Okay.
法林先生  你是他们的医疗监护人
Mr. Fallin, you're the medical guardian.
由你来决定要不要做检查
lt's up to you to approve the testing.
你看  达姆森并没有意见  那我们还等什么
You know, Damsen might have a point. Why not wait?
你的意思是安置好他们然后再做检查吗
You mean place them and then test them?
当然
Sure.
好吧  如果他们感染了艾滋  再接受治疗  这样行不通
Well, if they're infected, they need treatment. It's simple.
行不通吗
Simple?
我并不想把孩子安顿在某个家庭
I don't want to place a child with a family
之后再有这样的事情来破坏这个家庭
and then have something like this disrupt it.
最好还是先把一切都解决好
lt's better to have all the cards on the table.
好  那就这样定
Okay. Go ahead.
你正在用不正当的手段来影响康纳先生的意愿
You're contesting Mr. Connor's will on the basis of undue influence.
里特尔小姐  和一个大她两倍的男人成为情侣
Miss Little... used a romantic relationship with a man twice her age
以此来影响他的遗产规划
to, uh... influence his estate planning.
我的委托人和康纳先生是真爱
My client was in love with Mr. Connor.
在他生病期间一直照顾他
She cared for him during his long illness.
你的委托人是在操控一个精神脆弱的垂死的老人
Your client manipulated a dying man who was mentally frail.
而你们正提供一百万的慈善捐款
You're holding up a million-dollar charitable contribution
- 给一个非营利机构  - 不  不是这样的  阿尔文
- to a not-for-profit agency. - No. No, Alvin.
我的委托人在就遗产问题起诉
My client is suing Mr. Connor's estate.
那现在  如果你的委托人想要索赔  你知道的
Now... if your client wants to file a claim, you know...
她可以等着
she's free to get in line.
你只能等着了
You'll just have to wait it out.
这就是他们的目的了
That's exactly what they want me to do.
他们知道我现在有麻烦
They know I'm in trouble.
联盟极有可能在解决完遗产问题前就垮掉
That the Alliance could go under before this is resolved.
那你需要多少钱才能维持
How much do you need to keep going?
坚持到年底还需要五万美金吧
Fifty grand to keep me going till the end of the year.
在聚会上能凑齐吗
Will you make that from the party?
你指的是今天上午我们提到的那个聚会吗
You mean the party that l threw together this morning?
能有二十个人到我就很满足了
I'll be lucky if I can get twenty people to show up.
往好的方向想想
Oh, it might work.
靠一个化装舞会
A masquerade party.
我可能是世界上最蠢的人了
I gotta be the dumbest person on the planet.
- 不  你不是  - 我甚至都付不起焦油坑的场地费
- You're not. - I can't even afford The Tar Pit.
阿尔文  里特尔小姐
Alvin. Miss Little.
- 你好  尼克  - 我们认识吗
- Nick. - Have we met?
呃  尼克  是律所的志愿者
Uh... Nick, uh... volunteers at the Clinic.
他是  巴顿的儿子
He's, uh... he's Burton's son.
哦  嗨
Oh, hey.
你看这个了吗
You see this?
看过了
Yeah.
莱恩·盖金和肯·波特  还记得他们吗
Len Getkin and Ken Potter. Remember them?
推销员  欠我们大概三万
Merchandising guys. Owe us about thirty grand.
是的  我给他们提了个主意  在所有商品上加一个标语
Right. Well, I sold them on an idea. A slogan for all that merchandise.
信任
''Believe.''
- 好主意  - 是啊
- Good for you. - Yeah.
哦  而且  我跟露露的助理聊到了周六的化装舞会
Oh, and I spoke to, uh, Lulu's assistant about that masquerade party on Saturday.
- 听起来会有意思  - 是的
- Sounds like a lotta fun. - Right.
我就职于一家叫领军制造的公司
I work for a company called Principal Products.
他们希望能得到你的作品的使用授权  用于T恤和帽子等
They're interested in licensing your art... for, uh... for T-shirts, hats.
使用授权
Licensing?
他们希望能付你一些费用
They want to... they want to pay you money
之后把你的作品放到他们的产品上  比如T恤
to use your art to apply to their products, like on a T-shirt.
他们想要把它放在衣服上
They want to put it on a... a T-shirt?
- 就是这个意思  - 然后他们想把衣服卖掉
- Exactly. - And then they want to sell the T-shirt.
所以你的想法  呃
Well, your message is, uh...
现在非常重要  其他一切都已经准备就绪
well, it's very important right now, things being the way they are.
我  我不太明白  关于销售的部分
I'm... I'm not, uh, sure about the, uh... selling part.
墨菲先生  关于那部分
Well, Mr. Murphy, the... the deal, uh...
在销售之前就会付给你足够一年生活的费用
There's enough money up-front to cover your living expenses for a year.
而且  如果这个方法效果显著
And, if this works out, there...
还会有更多的钱  也许是足够你舒服过完一辈子的
well, there might be enough money to keep you comfortable for the rest of your life.
信任
Believe.
我的客户想通过你的俱乐部来提高艾滋病的意识
My client's trying to get into your sports club to increase AIDS awareness.
他们一周只会来两次
And they're only interested in coming twice a week
发一下避孕套并且做一些免费的艾滋病检测
to distribute condoms and provide free AIDS testing.
好吧  但这并不是人们来这里玩的目的
Right. See, that's not exactly  why people come to this club.
明白
Okay.
这是男性体育俱乐部
This is a men's athletic club.
大家都是来健身的
The guys work out.
也是来享受一些私密的友情
Enjoy the private camaraderie.
通过这种情感关系  你知道的  互相会传染艾滋
And by camaraderie, do you mean giving each other AIDS,
而且还会再传染给他们的妻子  女朋友  和孩子
which then gets spread to their wives and girlfriends and their children?
要知道  很多孩子一出生就已经被感染了
Babies are being born infected. You must know that.
女士  我想说  即使你提供了一百万个避孕套和免费测试
Lady. I mean... you could offer a million condoms and tests.
这的这些家伙  他们也是不会用的
The guys here... they're not gonna take 'em.
杰克
Jake?
露露
Lulu.
嗯  我就是
Um... I was just...
我
l...
我是
I was...
露露  你还好吗
Lulu, are you okay?
我想做一个母亲  真的  但是  现在真的不是一个合适的时机
I want to be a mother, I do... but, uh... now is just not really the time.
而且  尼克他  呃
And, uh... Nick, is, uh...
我弄不懂他
He's so unreadable.
我  我并不清楚他是不是也这样想的
l... l... I'm not really sure that he really wants to do this anyway.
那么  你爱他吗
I mean, do you love him?
我想我是爱他的
I think so.
可能大部分时候是爱他的  但是之后
Uh... most of the time I do, but then...
理解
Right.
这感觉真的很奇怪  你知道吗
This is really weird... you know?
我的意思是  真不敢相信  我就这样全都跟你说了
I mean, I just... I can't believe I'm... I'm dumping all this on you.
你只是
You were just...
错误的时间  错误的地点
Wrong place at the wrong time.
我们并不是特别了解彼此
We don't know each other very well.
其实我们互相是了解的  露露
We... we know each other, Lulu.
嗯  你知道  我经常觉得你有一点
Um... you know, I guess I always thought that you were kind of--
- 不  不  - 别打断我  我只是想说
- No, no. - Wait, but I just want to say this.
呃  我希望你能注意安全
Uh... I hope you're being careful.
你知道的  我是天主教徒  而且是工人阶级
You know, I was... I was raised Catholic and, uh... and working class, right?
所以  请理解我的话有些那方面的色彩
So, uh, understand what I'm about to say is gonna be kinda colored by that.
你什么都不用解释的
Oh, you don't have to explain anything to me.
这件事跟我并没有什么关系
Well, this isn't about me.
不  留下这个孩子  露露
No. Have the baby, Lulu.
你会是一个特别好的妈妈
You're gonna be a wonderful mother.
而且尼克  尽管他
And Nick, despite his, uh... his, uh...
他就那个样
the way he is,
但是尼克会是一个很可靠的父亲
Nick's gonna be a solid dad.
父亲  呃
Dad, uh...
你还有你妈妈的订婚戒指吗
you still have Mom's engagement ring?
当然有
Yeah. I do.
那么  如果  呃  如果
Well, if, uh... if...
如果你同意的话
if it's okay with you...
能不能把它给我
I'd like to have it.
明天我给你带来
I'll bring it in tomorrow.
谢谢
Thank you.
嘿
Hey.
嗯
Uh...
- 路易莎·阿切尔  - 在这
- Louisa Archer? - Oh.
他们准备好了
They're ready. Uhm...
呃  我可以进去吗
Uh... it's okay if I come in?
我觉得你还是在外边等我吧
I think you should stay here.
我马上就好
I'll be right back.
- 可以吗  - 好吧
- Okay? - Yeah.
嘉里·瓦伦汀
Carrie Valentine?
怎么样
How'd it go?
呃  已经五周了
Uh... well, I'm five weeks.
五周了吗
Five weeks?
是啊  还很早  尼克
Yeah. It's really early, Nick.
已经五周了
lt's five weeks.
现在它还只是一些小细胞
lt's just a cluster of cells right now.
是啊
Right.
只是一些小细胞
Just a little cluster of cells.
- 哦
- Oh...
- 艾塔  - 嗨
- Etta. - Hi.
- 在做什么  - 在拉你的衣服
- What are you doing? - Pulling your shirt.
好吧  你怎么在这
Right. You supposed to be in here?
嘘
Shh.
我找不到艾塔了
I can't find Etta.
呃  我也没看到她
Oh, l... haven't seen her.
嗨  小宝贝
Hi, sweetie.
- 嗨  -嗨
- Hi. - Hi.
马库斯正在外边搭一个城堡  要去帮帮他吗
Marcus is outside making a castle. Do you want to help him?
再见  艾塔
Bye, Etta.
谢谢你
Thank you.
艾塔的HIV检测成阳性
Etta's HIV-positive.
那马库斯呢
What about Marcus?
他没问题
Marcus is fine.
但是原本想领养他们的家庭已经不行了
But, the family that was interested in fostering them is out.
所以我需要给他们找一个新的地方
So I need to find a new placement,
但是  你要知道  能接纳一个四岁的艾滋病患儿的家庭并不多
but, you know, there's not a lot for a four-year-old with HIV.
我感觉自己把一切都搞砸了
I guess I screwed the whole thing up
用桌子上那些烂纸把一切都搞砸了
with that whole... with the cards on the freaking table thing.
不是你的问题
No.
她只是一个那么可爱的小女孩
She's just such a sweet little girl.
我宁愿在她做检查之前先让那个家庭了解她
I wish I'd let the family get to know her before I had her tested.
不  是因为我的问题
No, it was my call.
不  不是
No it wasn't.
- 我找到了他们的爸爸  - 他在哪
- I found the dad. - Where is he?
他在晨间高地那一个专门为艾滋病人提供的寄宿公寓
He's at a boarding house in Morningside for people with AIDS.
哦
Oh.
麦先生
Mr. Wheat?
门是开着的
The door's open.
今天不想吃东西了
Don't want to eat today.
那不是我们今天来的目的
That's not what we're here for.
什么吃的都不要
Don't want any food.
我们不是来发吃的的  麦先生
We're not here to deliver food, Mr. Wheat.
我叫苏珊·佩尔  是一名社会工作者
My name is Suzanne Pell, and I'm a social worker.
这位是尼克·法林  他是一名律师
And this is Nick Fallin. He's a lawyer.
我们是想来跟你聊一下你的孩子艾塔和马库斯的
We're here about your children Etta and Marcus.
我妻子在哪
Where is my wife?
你的妻子四天前已经去世了
Your wife passed away four days ago.
她死了
She died?
我们需要为你的孩子们找一个新家
We need to find a home for your children.
我帮不上什么忙
I'm... I'm no good for that.
麦先生  我们有一些问题
Mr. Wheat, we have some problems.
问题  什么问题  关于我的孩子吗
Problems? What, with my kids?
是的  艾塔是一个艾滋病患者  我们需要给她找一个家
Yes. Etta is HIV-positive, and we need to find her a home.
你知道谁有可能领养他的吗
Do you know anyone who might take her?
马库斯也是吗
ls Marcus sick, too?
他没有
No.
我妻子  她是死于艾滋吗
My wife... she died from the AIDS?
是的  先生  她是死于艾滋病
Yes, sir. Yes, she did.
你觉得是我造成这一切的吗
You think I did this to them?
呃  我就把我名片放这边了
Um... I'm just gonna leave our information here.
黑人本来应该是很强壮的
Black men are supposed to be strong.
应该是合格的父亲
Supposed to be fathers.
很抱歉打扰你了
Sorry to disturb you.
我  我已经结婚了  而且我很爱我的妻子
l... was a married man... and I loved my wife.
我也很爱我的孩子
And I loved my kids.
我是个男人  你明白吗
I was a man, you get me?
那么一万美元  立即支付
So ten thousand dollars, payable immediately.
再加上出售后收入的百分之二
Plus two percent of the adjusted gross revenue.
是一笔划算的买卖
lt's... it's a good deal.
相信我
Believe me.
呃
Uh...
不要做红色的T恤
No red T-shirts.
因为太阳的颜色  当然了
Because the color of the sun, naturally.
而且  同理也不要做橙色的
And, uh... no orange for the same reason.
还有  不要做高领毛衣
And, uh... no turtlenecks.
不
No...
仅限二号铅笔
Number 2 pencils only.
也不要做书包或者午餐盒
And no backpacks or lunchboxes.
可以做一些帽子  但是不要后面带纽扣的那种
Hats are okay, but not with the, uh, kind with the snaps in the back.
还有  你之前说到了钥匙链
And, uh, you said something about key chains.
是的
Right.
呃
Ah--
一定不要做钥匙链
Absolutely no key chains.
什么  不能做钥匙链
Wha... No key chains?
有一些人
S-Some people...
有些人他们不用钥匙
Some people don't have keys.
而且  呃
And, uh... uh...
不要在周一卖这些东西
no selling of these products on Mondays.
我们要让一周在轻松愉快中开始
We have to let the week begin easy.
好吧  墨菲先生  你说的这些都很有意思
Well, Mr. Murphy, uh... all this is very interesting,
但是恐怕你的要求都不能被答应
but I'm afraid none of your requests can be granted.
可能除了不做橙色或红色T恤这一条
Except for maybe the idea about no orange or red T-shirts,
这个还是可以理解的
which does kinda make some sense.
好吧
Okay.
好  那我们就这样说定了
Okay, so we're agreed.
那一万美金的独家许可权费用
Then ten thousand dollars for exclusive licensing rights
加上收入的百分之二
plus two percent after break even.
并且不能做红色或橙色的
And no orange or red.
是的  不能做红色或橙色
No. No orange or red.
不做橙色和红色
No orange or red.
可以
Fine.
好了  那么  我就开始商标核名了
Okay, so I'll... I'll get the trademark search started.
基尔斯滕  早上好
Morning, Kirsten.
有一个多伦多寄给我的包裹吧
I'm expecting a package from Toronto.
巴顿
Burton?
嘿  阿尔文  最近怎么样
Hey, Alvin. How are ya?
嗨
Hi.
那个起草沃伦·康纳遗嘱的律师
The, uh, lawyer who, uh, drafted Warren Connor's wilI's gonna testify
将会证明沃伦没有反复修改文件
that Warren was not unduly influenced to revise the document.
所以我向法庭提出了这项动议  要求驳回诉求
So I filed a motion with the Orphan's Court to have the contest dismissed.
听证会定于下周进行
The hearing's scheduled for next week.
我们会出席的
We'll be there.
法林先生  一百万美元  没了它  很多人会死
Mr. Fallin. A million dollars. Without it, people will die.
饱受饥饿的艾滋病患者会连一口热饭都没有
People with AIDS who are hungry won't receive hot meals.
会没有处方药
They won't get their prescription drugs.
里特尔小姐  我清楚你是好心的
Miss Little, I'm... I'm sure your intentions are... the best,
但这也是一个家庭的问题
but this is... this is a family matter.
如果我这周能通过这个聚会筹集五万
lf I could just get fifty grand out of the party this weekend,
那我就还能再坚持三十天
I could hold out for another thirty days.
好吧  我有时间
Well... I have some free time.
而且我是一个很厉害的筹款人
And I'm a pretty good fundraiser.
也许我们可以  呃  集思广益
Maybe we could, uh... brainstorm some ideas.
我从来没有关心过沃伦
I never really cared for Warren.
是么
Oh?
让这种男人做些好事的唯一方法
The only way to get a man like that to do something good
就是和他上床
was to... sleep with him.
这就是我这样做的原因
That's why I did it.
我哥哥十年前死于艾滋
My brother died of AIDS... ten years ago.
匹兹堡有数千人需要帮助
There are thousand of people in Pittsburgh who need help.
我会竭尽所能
I do what it takes.
我很不好意思
I'm embarrassed.
其实  我喜欢你
Look... I like you.
我并不想让你觉得  我是真的关心他
I don't want you to think that... l... I did care about him.
我们很了解彼此
We knew each other.
但是  这很复杂
But... it was complica--
嘿
Hey.
- 嘿  -请进
- Hey. - Come in.
请坐
Sit down.
路过银行 拿上戒指
Went by the bank. Picked up the ring.
这是我1965年用全部身家买的
lt's all I could afford in 1965.
将近一克拉
lt's almost a carat.
在我印象中应该更大一点
I remember it being a little bigger than that.
很漂亮
lt's beautiful.
事实上  是你妈妈选的  你知道吗
Actually, your mother picked it out, you know?
她总是领先我一步
She was always a step ahead of me, you know?
她说她不想我给她惊喜  所以她自己选了一个
She told me she didn't want me to surprise her, so she picked it out.
你知道  当我向你妈妈求婚的时候
You know, when I proposed to your mother,
她  其实早就知道  但是  她表现的特别惊讶
she... she was expecting it anyway, but she, uh... she acted surprised.
所以  不管怎样  呃  我  我都想祝福你
Well, anyway, uh... l... I want to wish you...
尼古拉斯  我很爱你的妈妈
Nicholas, I loved your mother.
我希望你能明白
I hope you know that.
我想一辈子都能和她在一起
I wanted to spend my life with her.
但是事情就是不能如意  所以  我  我放手了
Things just... fell apart, and l... l... I let it go.
我  我放手了
I let... I let her go.
我很遗憾
I regret that.
但是
Well...
你会做得更好
you'll do better.
我爱你  孩子
I love you, son.
我也爱你  爸爸
I love you, too, Dad.
斯坦利高地集体救助所
Stanley Heights Group Shelter?
这是唯一一个可以接受艾滋病患儿的地方
lt's the only shelter that can handle HIV-positive children.
有多少十岁以下的孩子住在那
How many kids under ten live there?
- 并不多  - 好吧
- Not many. - Right.
我检查了县里的每一张床
I've checked every bed in the county.
我的意思是  我们可以分开他们  但是艾塔还是要去斯坦利高地
I mean, we could split them up, but Etta's still gonna have to go to Stanley Heights.
尼克  哦  嗨  苏珊
Nick. Oh, hi, Suzanne.
有几个关于麦的案子的人想要见你
There's a couple here to see you regarding the Wheat case.
在整个悲剧发生之前  达里尔认识凯文·麦
Daryl used to know Calvin Wheat before the whole tragedy.
他们之前一起在体育馆打篮球
They played basketball together at the gym.
是的
Right.
昨天凯文给我打电话的时候我正在上班
I was at work yesterday when I got the call from Calvin.
我已经很多年没跟他联系了
I hadn't... talked to him in years.
他跟我说了关于他的孩子的问题
He told me about the problems with his children.
就是他们没有能去的合适的地方
That... they didn't have any place to go.
小艾塔还生病了
That little Etta was sick.
所以我跟妮可说了这件事
So I talked to Nicole about it.
我们为此祈祷  并且
And we prayed about it and...
今天早上我们决定
And this morning we decided.
这样做是对的
This is the right thing.
莱基先生莱基太太  你们清楚艾塔会有一些特殊需求吗
Mr. and Mrs. Lakey, you understand that Etta has special needs?
而且你们准备好接受关于这类疾病的教育了吗
And you're prepared to educate yourself about the disease?
事实上  我们并不太了解艾滋病
We don't know much about it. It's true.
但是我们可以学习
But we can learn.
好的
Okay.
那么  既然你们已经来了  那需要你们填写这份文件
Well, while you're here, we'll have you fill out the paperwork.
然后我们将在今天晚些时候安排家庭学习和医疗评估
And then we'll schedule a home study and medical evaluations for later today.
没问题
No problem.
那好的
Okay, then.
我们什么时候可以见一见孩子们
When can we see the kids?
嘿
Hey.
怎么了
What's up?
哦  卫生检查员说
Oh, the health inspector said...
哦  你让给我们进行突然采访的家伙
Oh... that guy you had pay us a surprise visit.
是的
Right.
那个发现我们符合标准的家伙
The guy who found our facilities up to code.
嗯  他说你在等我
Right. He said you'd be expecting me.
所以  我带来了避孕套
So... I have the condoms.
右边那扇门
That door on the right.
你可以把他们和其他的都放在这
You can put it in here with the rest of 'em.
不行  放在这没人会看到
No. No one's gonna see them.
那你是要随身带着这些东西
Then take them with you.
什么意思  我没明白
Know what? I don't get you.
我所希望的就是你能给大家一个安全的选择
All I'm asking is that you give people the option to be safe.
要知道  这是为了阻止一些事情的发生
You know, stop an avoidable thing from happening.
好吧  我没时间应付这些
Okay. I don't have time for this.
扔在这  或者带着走  随便你
Leave them. Take them. It's your call.
随便我
My call?
我就是这个意思  随便你  女士
That's what I just said. It's all up to you, lady.
他们想把这些扔进一个脏兮兮的壁橱里
And they wanted to just toss them in some moldy closet
就是他们扔其他避孕套和艾滋病资料的地方
where they hide all of their condoms and AIDS literature.
所以这个让你觉得可能
And so this makes you think that maybe...
是的  也许我只是因为自己的感受
Yeah. Maybe I'm just looking for all the bad things
看到的都是不好的方面
to justify the way that I feel.
呃
Ah...
是的  是的
Yeah. Yeah.
不不不  打电话给欧盟的人
No, no, no. Just call the European Union guy.
是的  这样就可以
Right. It... it's easy.
你能处理好的
You can get it done.
谢谢
Thank you.
呃  只是  尽职地调查关于  信任  的事情
Just, uh... due diligence on this ''Believe'' thing.
- 呃  你需要去处理这件事吗  - 不用
- Oh, you need to take care of it? - No.
所以  你说的是战争  贫穷  艾滋病  那为什么要把孩子卷进来
So, uhm... you were saying, war, poverty, AIDS... Why bring a kid into that?
谁知道呢
I guess.
你知道  当我妈妈企图自杀的时候  她
You know, when my mother attempted suicide, she, uhm...
呃  我觉得  她  她特别沮丧
Well, I mean, she... she got very depressed and...
然后就做了一些傻事
and then she did something stupid.
什么意思
What do you mean?
事实上  她并不是真的想死
Well, she didn't really want to die.
她只是害怕了
She was afraid, that's all.
我的意思是  如果你要问我的看法
I mean, if you're asking my opinion...
你知道我怎么想的
you know what I think.
哦  嘿  有时间吗
Oh, hey. You got a second?
不好意思  我正要回家
No, I'm trying to get home.
- 莱基一家通过了他们的家庭学习  - 很好
- The Lakeys passed their home study. - Great.
但是到医疗检测时  莱基先生拒绝做血液检测
But at the medical exam, Mr. Lakey refused to take the blood test.
- 他拒绝做血液检测  - 是的
- He refused his blood test? - Yeah.
- 我的意思是  这是他的权利  但是我  - 好吧
- I mean, it's within his rights, but l-- - Okay.
- 在这种情况下  - 好的  我会再了解一下
- Under the circumstances-- - Yeah, I'll look into it.
我得回家了
I gotta get home.
今天怎么样
How was your day?
还不错
Fine.
那很好啊
Good.
你呢
Yours?
也挺好
Fine.
很好
Good.
你觉得我们真的要戴面具去这个聚会吗
Do you think we really have to wear masks to this party?
我也不知道
I don't know.
因为我不知道哪里
'Cause I just don't know where...
我想   我们也许可以戴万圣节的面具
I mean, I guess we could wear Halloween masks,
但是我不认为这是他们想得到的效果
but I don't think that's what they have in mind.
我也不知道
I don't know.
呃  你吃饭了吗
Um... did you eat anything?
还没
No.
那  冰箱里还有半个三明治
Well, there's a half a sandwich in the fridge.
现在我们面临着一个更大的抉择  尼克
We have a much bigger decision in front of us, Nick,
你知道  比结婚更重要的
than getting married, you know?
我们需要做一个更加重要的决定
We have a much... much bigger decision.
不管怎样  我并不想只是因为怀孕了就结婚
I don't want to get married just because I'm pregnant... anyway.
我不太明白你
I just don't get you.
我不知道你为什么不跟我谈这件事
I don't know why you didn't talk to me about this, you know?
跟我谈谈你正考虑做什么样的改变
Just talk to me about what you're thinking for a change
因为  这并不需要多么浪漫
because... this doesn't have to be romantic-- our thing.
要知道  我们应该像成年人一样
You know, we really should be like adults,
我们应该好好谈谈然后做出决定
and we should talk about things and then make decisions.
你知道
You know...
我  如果你不想嫁给我  我并不会介意
l... I don't... I don't care if you don't want to marry me.
没关系的  我只是  你知道
lt's all right. I just... You know...
我知道我已经准备好做一个父亲了
I know that I'm ready to be a father.
我确定
I know that.
帽子真好看
lt's a really nice hat.
是的  我相信
Yeah. I believe.
我收到了一封芝加哥律师事务所的信
So... I received a letter from the Chicago law firm
代表了富山清酒的利益
that represents Fujiyama Sake's U.S. interests.
富山清酒的最高端产品就叫做信任
Fujiyama's top shelf Sake is called Believe.
信任清酒
Believe Sake.
其中文字是被红色的太阳包围的
The text of which is surrounded by a red sun.
所以  我们现在面临这个问题
So... we have this problem.
怎么回事
Excuse me?
他们  他们威胁将会提起联邦诉讼
Well, they're... they're threatening a Federal lawsuit
如果我们使用他们的商标
if we use their trademark.
我们已经打印了七万五千件产品
We printed seventy-five thousand of these.
我绝不会同意
I never give you the go-ahead.
你告诉我们要动作快
You told us to act fast.
好吧  我很抱歉  你们不能卖这些T恤和帽子
Well... I'm sorry, you can't sell the T-shirts or the hats
或者  或者钥匙链
or the... or the key chains.
怎么会这样
How did this happen?
并没有重要明确的指示
There were no significant indicators.
你没有检查日本的商标吗
You... you didn't check Japan for trademarks?
我查了文字和字母  并没有什么明确的问题
Well, I ran the text and the letters, and nothing significant came back.
你没有查日本的吗
You didn't check Japan?
所以他们不能给我钱
So they can't give me the money?
因为这家叫富士清酒的公司
Because of this company, Fujiyama.
富士清酒
Fujiyama Sake.
弗雷德  你知道富士清酒是什么吗
Do... do you know what Fujiyama Sake is, Fred?
好吧  我知道清酒  上帝清酒
Well, I know what Sake is, for God's sake.
我曾经住在日本
I lived in Japan.
你在日本待过
You... you were in Japan?
当时参军  曾经住在日本
When I was in the Army, I lived in Japan.
我在日本的时候  会喝清酒  所有人都喝的
When I was in Japan, I drank Sake. Everyone drinks Sake.
麦先生
Mr. Wheat?
是的  怎么了
Yeah, what?
我两天前就来这了
I came by here two days ago.
我的孩子们都还好吗
Are my kids okay?
达里尔·莱基
Daryl Lakey.
怎么了
Yeah?
你能跟我解释清楚吗
Can you help me understand something?
什么
What?
你和他有关系吗
Were you involved with him?
你什么意思
What do you mean?
你和他做过吗  他  是你的伴侣之一吗
Did you have sex with him? Was he... was he one of your partners?
麦先生  这就是我想了解的
See, here's my problem, Mr. Wheat.
如果我把你的孩子们送到莱基家生活
lf I give your children to the Lakeys
而且如果莱基先生是艾滋病患者而莱基夫人并不知情
and if Mr. Lakey's HIV-positive and if Mrs. Lakey doesn't know,
那么就又有一个家庭要被毁了
then another family will be destroyed...
而你的孩子们又被卷入其中
with your children in the middle of it... again.
莱基先生  我请您独自过来的原因
Mr. Lakey, the reason I asked you to come in here by yourself--
能让我们单独聊一会吗
Can you leave us a minute?
谢谢
Thank you.
我和凯文·麦先生聊过了
I spoke with Calvin Wheat.
嗯
Okay.
由于你拒绝做血液检测  所以我去找了他
I went to see him because of your refusal to give a blood sample.
嗯
Okay.
他证实了一些事情
He confirmed some things.
法林先生  我是不会做血液测试的
I don't take blood tests, Mr. Fallin.
这就是为什么最初有像凯文一样的黑人会得病
That's how black men get diseases like Calvin's in the first place.
凯文·麦并不是从针头感染艾滋的  是吧
Calvin Wheat didn't contract HIV from a needle, all right?
我不知道他怎么得的
I don't know how he got it.
好吧
Right.
莱基先生
Mr. Lakey,
你现在做的事情  照顾他的孩子们这件事  是一件好事
what you're doing, taking in his children, is a very good thing.
但是如果你是艾滋病人  而且如果你感染给你的
But if you're HIV-positive and then if you infect your--
你给我闭嘴
You shut your mouth.
我不是同性恋  所以你最好给我闭嘴
I am not a faggot... so you shut your mouth.
我在努力做一些好事  法林先生
I am trying to do the right thing here, Mr. Fallin.
你最好别逼我改变主意
But don't make me change my mind.
明白吗
Understand?
别逼我改变主意
Don't make me change my mind.
你想做什么
What do you want to do?
这是你的建议
lt's your recommendation.
你的安置计划
Your placement.
总比在斯坦利高地好
lt's better than Stanley Heights.
希望如此吧
Hope so.
太复杂了
lt's complicated.
嘿
Hey.
嗨
事情顺利吗
How are things?
- 还不错  还不错  - 那就好
- Fine. Fine. - Good.
你需要些什么吗
Do you need anything?
就想知道事情进展怎么样
Just wanted to know how things went.
还没求婚呢
Haven't done it yet.
哦
Oh...
我就是想让大家都知道
I just want to let everybody know
我们已经筹到一半了——两万六千美元
we've reached our halmay point-- twenty-six thousand dollars.
所以  请慷慨解囊
So please, empty out your pockets,
拿出信用卡  捐赠  捐赠  再捐赠
put it on the credit card, and give, give, give.
你知道  我感觉并不怎么好
You know... I don't... I don't feel so great.
你是不是需要一些水或者其他东西
Maybe... Do you... do you want some more water or something?
不  不  不需要了
Oh, no. No.
也许我们需要点新鲜空气或者
Maybe we need some air or...
好的  我想我们还回家了
lt's okay. I think I'm just gonna go home.
是的   我们该回家了
Yeah. Let's... Iet's just go.
- 好好玩  - 好的
- Have fun. - All right.
- 失陪了  - 晚安
- Sorry. - Good night.
晚安
Good night.
嘿  你知道吗
Hey, you know what?
你之前答应过要帮忙的  所以你应该留下来的
You should just stay because you promised you'd help with the ramle.
- 哦  其他人做就行了  - 不  不 不行
- Oh, someone else can do it. - No, no, no.
就留下来吧  我自己回家
Just... just stay, please. I'm... I'm gonna go home.
我没事  我就是要回家了
I'm fine. I just need to go home.
晚点见
I'll see you later.
好吧
Okay.
现在 我们十名幸运获奖者中的一个
Now for the first of our ten lucky winners
获得漂亮的陶瓷小丑玩偶
of this beautiful ceramic jester doll,
由林肯大街隐藏宝藏捐赠
donated by Hidden Treasures on Lincoln Street.
4084.
号码是4084的朋友  请上台来领取你的奖品
Whoever has ticket 4084, come on up and get your prize.
我觉得娃娃都是用报纸包起来的
I think the dolls are wrapped in newspaper,
或者在下面一个大纸板箱里
or they're in a big cardboard box, down there.
祝贺
Congratulations.
嗨
Hi.
- 是我  - 谁啊
- It's me. - Who?
是我
lt's me.
玩得开心吗
Having fun?
挺好的
Right.
你的女伴呢
Where's your date?
呃  她  她先走了
Uh... she... she left.
哦
Oh.
嗯  我动用了一些关系
So, uhm... I pulled some strings
这样孩子们下周末就可以和莱基一家在一起
so that the kids could be with the Lakeys by next weekend.
很好  很好  这样就太
Good. Good. That must've been, um...
有点复杂
lt's complicated.
是的
Yeah.
复杂吗
Complicated?
我们已经募集了51211美金
We've raised fifty-one thousand, two hundred and eleven dollars.
嗨
Hi.
聚会怎么样
How was the party?
还不错
Fine.
呃  我一直在想
Uh... I've been thinking.
我不想去堕胎
I don't want to have an abortion.
那太好了
Well, that's great.
这就是我一直想的
That's what I've been thinking.
好啊
Okay.
好的
所以  你想进来吗
So... you want to get in?
尼克  快点  进来
Nick... come on, get in.
Xgun擦枪小组 有偿招募译制成员 诚邀阁下
加入Q群：545053435
请注明职务：翻译、听译、aegisub特效（熟练手）
对字幕有任何意见和建议的同学请加Q群：544487177